CLARISSE CASI CARINO

Full Stack Developer

(+33) 605 525 833 * casi.carino.business@gmail.com * github.com/clarissecasicarino * 3 Rue de Lasteyrie 75016 Paris

Summary

An extremely versatile developer capable of handling front-end and back-end technologies, creating visually captivating user experiences, and developing seamless Application Programming Interfaces. Ultimately, a fast learner and a team-oriented professional with the ability to translate business requirements into concrete software solutions.

Experience

SM Retail Pasay, Philippines
Full Stack Developer (Full-time) 09/2023 - 03/2024

- Architected the creation of "Link Card" middleware, streamlining the card number linking process to enhance member engagement
- Led the development of the "OTP Generation and Validation" middleware, seamlessly connecting with an existing API to enhance data security through two-way authentication, thereby ensuring a robust user experience
- Developed the "Register SMAC Member API," a middleware solution designed to streamline the registration process for new customers wishing to create an online account with SMAC. This innovative middleware also automates the creation of virtual loyalty cards for users

Flutter Developer (Full-time)

05/2023 - 03/2024

- Actively contributed as a key member of a four-person development team in the creation of a brand-new mobile application using Flutter framework
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams, including designers and backend developers, to design and develop a highly intuitive and
 user-friendly mobile application that aligns with the company's vision and goals
- Defined and implemented the application's core features and functionality to ensure a delightful user journey

Web and Mobile Applications Developer (Full-time)

09/2022 - 03/2024

- · Successfully transitioned into mobile development, showcasing adaptability and a rapid learning curve to become proficient in React Native framework
- Implemented a range of requested features by stakeholders, ensuring dynamic functionality and enhanced user experience on both web and mobile platforms
- · Demonstrated strong problem-solving skills by identifying and resolving complex technical issues in order to improve system performance

Zuitt Coding Bootcamp

Remote

Student Developer (Full-time)

04/2022 - 05/2022

- Capstone Project 1 Website Portfolio: Created a fully-responsive website using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap. URL: https://clarissecasicarino.github.io/webportfolio/
- Capstone Project 2 Backend Web Development: Engineered the backend server of Emporium Shopping Website using Express and Node.js with MongoDB as its database. GitLab Source Code: https://gitlab.com/b5207/capstone-2-ecommerce-api
- Capstone Project 3 Emporium Shopping Website: Developed an e-commerce platform using MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js). GitLab Source Code: https://gitlab.com/b5207/capstone03-emporium-final/emporium-website

Skills

Languages: Java, PHP, JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, Python

Styling and CMS: HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, Native Base, Bootstrap, React Bootstrap, Prismic

Tools: MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, React Native, Next.js, GraphQL, Flutter, MySQL, Amazon Web Services

Version Control and Code Hosting Platform: Git, GitHub, GitLab

Other Skills: Leadership, Time Management, API Development, Problem-Solving, Collaboration

Education

Schiller International University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

04/2024 - Present

Zuitt Coding Bootcamp

Certificate Course, Full Stack Web Development

04/2022 - 06/2022

Asia Pacific College

Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics with Specialization in Information Technology

06/2017 - 06/2019

Projects

Mamma Mia Tours: A Travel Agency website developed using Next.js 13, React, TypeScript, and Prismic CMS.

https://mamma-mia-tours.vercel.app/

Casi's Digital Space: Up-to-date web portfolio that showcases a cleaner and minimalistic design. https://casis-digital-space.vercel.app/